This time he's fighting for his life.
First Blood is a action, adventure, thriller film directed by Ted Kotcheff.
When former Green Beret John Rambo is harassed by local law enforcement and arrested for vagrancy, he is
forced to flee into the mountains and wage an escalating one-man war against his pursuers.
John Rambo, played by Sylvester Stallone.
Col. Samuel Trautman, played by Richard Crenna.
Hope Sheriff Will Teasle, played by Brian Dennehy.
State Police Capt. Dave Kern, played by Bill McKinney.
Deputy Sgt. Arthur Galt, played by Jack Starrett.
Deputy Balford, played by Michael Talbott.
First Blood is a 1982 American war action film starring
Sylvester Stallone as Vietnam War veteran John Rambo.
The film was directed by Ted Kotcheff and cowritten by Michael Kozoll, William
Sackheim and Stallone based on the 1972 novel First Blood by David Morrell.
The story follows Rambo who, after entering a small town and clashing with the police,
attempts to survive a manhunt using his expertise in survival and combat skills.
The film costars Richard Crenna as Rambo's mentor Colonel Sam
Trautman and Brian Dennehy as Sheriff Will Teasle.
First Blood was released in the United States on October 22, 1982.
Initial reviews were mixed, but the film was a box-office success, grossing $125.2 million and becoming the
13th-highest-grossing film at the domestic box office for the year and the seventh-highest-grossing film worldwide.
In 1985, it also became the first Hollywood blockbuster to be released in China, holding the
record for the largest number of tickets sold for an American film until 2018.
Since its release, it has been reappraised by critics, with many highlighting the roles of Stallone,
Dennehy and Crenna, and recognizing it as an influential film in the action genre.
The film's success spawned the Rambo franchise, consisting of four sequels (cowritten by and starring
Stallone), an animated television series, a comic books series, a novel series and several video games.
It was followed by Rambo: First Blood Part II, released in 1985.
The film explores themes of prison, guerrilla warfare,
dying and death, vietnam war, vietnam veteran.
The tone is dark and intense.